How do computers store characters like the letters of the alphabet?
计算机如何存储字符 比如字母表中的这些字母呢
Computers store everything as binary numbers.
计算机会把它们存储成二进制数字
Lowercase a, for instance,
比如说 小写的a
might be stored as 01100001.
会被存成 01100001
But how does the computer go back and forth storing a in
但计算机如何做到将字符 a 存成二进制数后
binary and then converting from binary to display the letter a?
还能将二进制数再转换成字符 a 呢
Computers do this conversion with encodings.
计算机是通过字符编码（encodings）来实现转换的
Encodings are a set of rules for converting between
字符编码是一套字符和对应二进制数
characters and the binary representation of those characters.
转换的规则
When the Internet first started,
在互联网建立之初
English was the most common language.
英语是最常用的语言
Hence, the most common encoding back then called ASCII,
因此 那时最常用的字符编码就是 ASCII
was specific to English.
是针对英语设计的
As the Internet proliferated,
随着互联网推广开来
ASCII couldn't handle all of the world's languages.
ASCII 不能处理全世界的各种语言了
Many languages contain more than the 26 characters in the English alphabet.
很多语言有不止英语字母表中的 26 种字母
Some Asian languages have thousands of unique characters.
一些亚洲的语言有几千个独立的字符
An international organization called the Unicode Consortium has created some
一个叫做统一码联盟（Unicode Consortium）的国际组织制定了
of the most flexible and comprehensive encodings to cover the world's languages.
灵活且全面的几个字符编码集来涵盖全世界的所有语言
Most of the data you'll come across is encoded with one of their encodings,
大多数你遇到的数据都是用他们的字符编码进行编码的
especially one called UTF-8.
尤其是 UTF-8 就是其中之一
However, you'll also come across datasets with other encodings like GB2312,
但是 你也会遇到用其他字符编码集 如GB2312 编码的数据集
for simplified Chinese characters,
这是中文简化字的字符编码集
and latin-1 for languages that use the Latin alphabet.
还有 latin-1 这是给含拉丁字母的语言使用的
The problem is that it's not easy to tell
问题来了 除非有人告诉你数据集的字符编码是什么
how a dataset was encoded unless somebody tells you.
不然分辨字符编码并不轻松
That's where the next programming exercise comes into play.
这是下一个编程练习要做的
I provided a dataset with a mystery encoding.
我们提供了一个未知字符编码的数据集
Your job will be to figure out what encoding was used.
你要找出它使用的是什么编码系统
This might seem like I'm being mean,
看起来是我在故意刁难
but figuring out encodings is a real world problem.
但找出字符编码是一个现实中经常遇到的问题
As you'll see, you can't read in a CSV file if you do not know the encoding.
你会发现 如果不知道字符编码 就无法读取 CSV 文件
In the exercise, you'll use the Panda's package
在练习中 你将使用 pandas 库
alongside a list of the encodings that come with the Python installation.
还有字符编码集的列表 这个列表在 Python 安装时就已装好
Check out the next part of the lesson to get started.
查看下一部分的课程 开始动手吧